Adam Simon

First name: Adam Last name: Simon

E-mail: hu.adamsimon@gmail.com

Mobil: 096 704 0887

SUPPLY CHAIN MANAGER

Supply chain management, development, implementation, demand planning

I have seven years job experience in retail FMCG industry in multinational environment. Dealt with projects and tasks mainly oriented in supply chain management: demand planning, capacity planning, process developments and project deployment. My latest job was leading a non-food merchandise planning team at one of the biggest retailer in Central Europe where I could widen my commercial experience in an international business environment. Experienced in food and non-food areas also.

EDUCATION

2003-2009 Corvinus University of Budapest / Faculty of Business Administration Department of Logistics and Supply Chain Management / Master Degree

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

sept.2015- jul. 2016 | CE Lead Merchandise Planning Manager at Tesco PLC

in this position I led a team of 4 people in order to maximise the store availability, keep the budget stock meanwhile fulfilling the sales and margin budgets at electrical small domestic appliances area. The operation of this area was taken over from the UK business in aug. 2015 by the Central Europe division. New team was set up where I was asked to lead one of the merchandise team.

KEY RESPONSIBITIES

- Keeping store availability: maintain 95% store stock availability for the following countries:
 - o Poland, Czech Republic, Slovakia, Hungary (400 stores)
- Managing and improving the DC goods in and out processes (supplier orders/ store allocation)
- Stock management: forcasting and planning stock value for short and long term periods
- Setting up internal budget/target for sales, profit stock, intake. Reforecast every period to manage and identify sales, profit and stock risk in the business. Highlighting risks to commecrial team.
- Working cross functionally with Buying and trade planning teams and wider local and international teams across Tesco to collaboratively deliver against sales/margin and stock targets
- Maintain good relaionship with supplier by having regular meeting to discuss forecast

ACHIVEMENTS

- set up a brand new team and mangage to start to work together as a team
- review and clear up the really neccessary range of products, discountinue the dupplication. These caused a long term stock reduction (avg. 20% decrease)
- set up new modell to separate low and high performance stores to handle them with different allocation models
- cooperate with the international development team in order to develop new allocation and forecasting tools simplyfing daily operational tasks.



may.2014- sept. 2015 | Project deployment manager at Tesco Hungary

in this position I was part of project team. The aim of the project was to implement a new automatic stores allocation system which replaced the previous one. I leaded one of the fouth stream: reporting and insight. Replacing the store allocation system opened a new possibities to handle system settings and simplified many operational processes.

KEY RESPONSIBITIES

- Execute the rollout plan related to the reporting stream Working close with the existing reporting team, review existing reports and create a detailed plan how to replace existing reports using the new system
- leading the workflow with the Central Europe IT team to harmonize different views of implementation priorities
- providing analysis, root cause, insight and leadership reports during each phases of the implementation and in ad/hoc situations

ACHIVEMENTS

- the overall project finished with great success as caused no negative impact on customers
- it was explored more function and possibities with the exisiting reporting team: opportunities to build effective database and real time reports widened
- at the final part of the project the project team was asked to support the Checz business in case of the same system implementation

marc.2012-apr. 2014 | Demand planner at Tesco Hungary

KEY RESPONSIBITIES

- build up a brand new process for providing sales and order forecast for suppliers with long delivery lead-time products
- participating in the project and keeping contact with demand planners in other countries and with the head project manager, regular weeky meetings
- after the processes were clarified and stabilized the improvement of the forecast accuracy became to key responsibity

ACHIVEMENTS

- During this period the forecast accuracy was improved by 24% (47%-->71%)
- Positive feedback from suppliers that that forecasts are useful and effectively helps their planning, improved supplier service level
- clear communication trough central European Tesco countries which was the key learnings in the

marc.2009-febr. 2012 | Distibution Center Volume planner at Tesco Hungary

KEY RESPONSIBITIES

- Forecasting and planning Distribution Centre (DC) goods out volume for a year period for financial controlling and DC's.
- capacity planning in rolling, monthl/weekly plans
- holding meetings with the DC and order system settings team to identify and resolve the main issues which can occur related to capacity planning and shop orders (especially at seasonal periods)
- creating special seasonal plans in the high turnover periods and around bank holidays (included building store stock)

ACHIVEMENTS

- Improved the method of forecasting with focusing more into sales perspective and less historical experience
- Mastered my skills in Excel, MS Access and VBA which allowed me to move forward into other analyst/specialist role

Other non-professional job experience:

jun. 2007 - sept. 2007 Noa's Ark Waterpark (USA, Wisconsin Dells, WI) Summerjob

Position: lifeguard

febr. 2008 – sept. 2008 Rentokil Initial UK Limited (UK, London) a job beside learning English

languages

Position: pest control technician

Languages:

• English: Strong written and verbal command of language

• German: Intermediate command of language

My Strength:

- excellent analytical skill
- system and process approach
- precision

IT skill:

- Knowledge and excellent use of the Microsoft Office products
- Professional handling of MS Excel (VBA also) and MS Access

15.07.2016.